[
    {
        "question": " Identify the correct answer ‘World Earth Day’ is celebrated to …………..",
        "options": [
            "Bring awareness about environmental protection",
            "Bring awareness to protect the trees",
            "Bring awareness to protect the atmosphere"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "When is the World Earth Day celebrated ?",
        "options": [
            "22nd April",
            "3rd May",
            "1st May"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What does sima means ?",
        "options": [
            "Silica + aluminium",
            "Silica + magnesium",
            "Silica + iron"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": " What happens when one goes deep into the interior of the earth ?",
        "options": [
            "Temperature increases",
            "Height increases",
            "Oxygen increases"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "When the lava comes out it is in …………… state.",
        "options": [
            "Liquid",
            "Solid",
            "Semi-solid"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The earth’s crust is made up of ……………",
        "options": [
            "Iron",
            "Rocks",
            "Magnesium"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Eruption of volcanoes and occurring of earthquakes infer that the …………. of the earth is hot.",
        "options": [
            "Surface",
            "Interior",
            "Crust"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The inner core of the interior of the earth is also called Nife which mean ……………",
        "options": [
            "Iron + magnesium",
            "Iron + aluminium",
            "Iron + Nickel"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Name of the following.The layer which extends upto 100 km from the surface of the earth.",
        "options": [
            "Atmosphere",
            "Magnetosphere",
            "Lithosphere"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": " Name the layer in which magma chambers are found.",
        "options": [
            "Sial",
            "Outercore",
            "Mantle"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The uppermost layer of the earth is the ……………",
        "options": [
            "Crust",
            "Mantle",
            "Care"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The core of the earth starts from …………… km.",
        "options": [
            "1200",
            "2900",
            "2500"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": " The …………… waves cannot pass through the outer core of the earth.",
        "options": [
            "Primary",
            "Secondary",
            "Surface"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The crust is the …………… of all the layers when compared to the mantle and the care.",
        "options": [
            "Thinnest",
            "Thickest",
            "Strongest"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Sial is composed of silica and …………..",
        "options": [
            "Magnesium",
            "Aluminium",
            "Iron"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": " When the earthquake comes the earth surface …………",
        "options": [
            "Breaks",
            "Tears",
            "Shakes"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "…………. Rocks are mainly found in continental crust.",
        "options": [
            "Granite",
            "Basalt",
            "Gabbro"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    }
   
]